Guide to the American Civil Liberties Union of North Carolina Records, 1960-2020; 1960-ongoing and undated RL.00012
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Legal Program Series, 1968-2006 and undated, 260 boxes
  - Case Files Subseries, 128 boxes
    - 2000s Case Files, 1998-2005
      - School violence prevention packet (Box 279)
      - Sheriff's bond information (Box 279)
      - Small claims forms (Box 279)
      - Fort Bragg school uniform case (Box 279)
      - Rutherford and Polk County school dress codes (Box 279)
      - Prayers at Elkin High graduation (Box 279)
      - Kicked out of school because of his hair style (Box 279)
      - City of Conover parade ordinance (Box 279)
      - Blue Ridge Community College prayer (Box 279)
      - Teacher proselytizing and physically abusing a child (Box 280)
      - Cabarrus County schools police interrogation policy (Box 280)
      - Legislative tuition grants (Box 280)
      - Asheville, NC Open Records Act (Box 280)
      - Rights of adult adoptees (Box 280)
      - High school student complaining about internet filters of a religious nature (Box 280)
      - Religious freedom at school, student disallowed from wearing a perfume with religious significance (Box 280)
      - Christmas program at juvenile training school (Box 280)
      - Elkin school uniforms (Box 280)
      - Prison hearing policy (Box 280)
      - English only (Box 280)
      - C.B. radio operation (Box 280)
      - First Presbyterian Child Development Center receiving federal funds (Box 280)
      - Complaint against Pineburke police (Box 280)
      - Durham: Flag ordinance (Box 280)
      - Statesville, driving while black (Box 280)
      - Muslim prisoner only served meals with pork (Box 280)
      - Denial of satanic religious material at an Eagle Springs training school (Box 280)
      - Harnett County Alternative School, illegal search of students (Box 280)
      - Denied loan, racial discrimination (Box 280)
      - Henderson middle school search policy (Box 280)
      - Graduation prayer (Box 280)
      - Orange High School newspaper distribution issue (Box 280)
      - In God We Trust inscribed at the Davidson County Governmental Center (Box 280)
      - Protester barred from a Kerry/Edwards campaign rally because of the anti-war message of his sign (Box 280)
      - Bush protest file, 2004 July 7 (Box 280)
      - Chapel Hill: lobbying ordinance (Box 280)
      - Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE) file (Box 280)
      - Son denied admission to high school, previous adjudicated juvenile offense (Box 280)
      - Daughter suspended from school for drawing a picture of an explosion, marked Columbine (Box 280)
      - Greenville: public school bible class (Box 280)
      - Son received pressure from his public school teacher to attend church (Box 280)
      - Demoted for writing a letter to the editor (Box 280)
      - Suspension of driver's license (Box 280)
      - HIV discrimination by Alamance County civil services (Box 280)
      - Religious blessing performed at a public school (Box 280)
      - Religious hymns at a public school (Box 280)
      - Police search of home without warrant (Box 280)
      - Prayer in a public school (Box 280)
      - Church of Divine Inspiration tax exemption issue (Box 280)
      - Strategic Lawsuit Against Public Participation (SLAPP suit) (Box 280)
      - HIV confidentiality (Box 280)
      - Forsyth County schools religious invocation (Box 281)
      - Fayetteville library censorship (Box 281)
      - City ordinance on church size discriminatory against minority communities (Box 281)
      - Lesbian not allowed to chaperone at child's school (Box 281)
      - American Legion 4018 Society disallowing female members (Box 281)
      - Internet filtered by service provider, no user options (Box 281)
      - Prohibited from handing out campaign cards at Rockingham folk festival (Box 281)
      - Double jeopardy (Box 281)
      - Southwestern Community College's censorship of bulletin board (Box 281)
      - Brunswick County EMT stipulation that EMTs must wear pants conflicts with her religious beliefs (Box 281)
      - Wiccan teacher suspension (Box 281)
      - Private prisons file: research into constitutionality (Box 281)
      - Recent State Supreme Court civil liberties decisions (Box 281)
      - Donor file (Box 281)
      - 2000 NC legislative session: examination of a bill involving confidentiality of mental health records (Box 281)
      - NC ACLU, legislative agenda, 2000-2002 (Box 281)
      - NORML faxes (Box 281)
      - Durham Political Signs Ordinance, 4 folders (Box 281)
      - Immigration, quick response team, 18 folders (Box 282)
      - Death penalty, articles, 2 folders (Box 282)
      - Cabarrus County, bible classes, 3 folders (Box 283)
      - Racial justice (Box 283)
      - Affiliate chapters relations policy (Box 283)
      - Ten Commandments in school, 3 folders (Box 283)
  - Legal Committee Subseries, 1995-2004, 7 boxes
    The members of the Legal Committee, consisting of the Legal Director, staff attorneys, and other staff met regularly to discuss cases and decide on which cases to accept, or which would only be investigative rather than pursued through the court system. Files include meeting minutes, retreats, and material on other decision-making processes.
    - Legal Committee 01, 1995-2004
      - NCCLU Legal Foundation Board of Directors Meeting, minutes: (Box 284)
        - 1970 May 15 - 1975 Oct. 31 (Box 284)
        - 1976 Jan. 9 - 1984 Oct. 26 (Box 284)
        - 1970-1984 duplicates (Box 284)
        - 1987 July 17 - 1996 Sept. 7 (Box 284)
        - 1987 July 17 - 1996 Sept. 7 duplicates (Box 284)
        - 1987 July 17 - 1997 Dec. 6 (Box 284)
        - 1987 July 17 - 1997 Dec. 6 duplicates (Box 284)
      - Legal Committee agendas and minutes
        - 1997 Dec. 6 - 2003 June 20 (Box 284)
        - 2003 Sept. 13 - 2004 Sept. 3 (Box 284)
      - Legal Committee Docket and ACLU policy documents (Box 284)
      - Legal Committee Meetings: (Box 285)
        - 1995 Jan. 20 (Box 285)
        - 1995 Mar. 18 (Box 285)
        - 1995 June 9 (Box 285)
        - 1995 Sept. 6 (Box 285)
        - 1995 Dec. 2 (Box 285)
        - 1996 Mar. 1 (Box 285)
        - 1996 June 7 (2 folders) (Box 285)
        - 1996 Sept. 7 (Box 285)
        - 1996 Dec. 6 (Box 285)
        - 1997 Apr. 11 (Box 285)
          Welfare reform included.
        - 1997 June 13 (Box 286)
        - 1997 Oct. 3 (2 folders) (Box 286)
        - 1997 Dec. 6 (Box 286)
        - 1998 Mar. 13 (Box 286)
        - 1998 June 12 (Box 286)
        - 1998 Oct. 16 (Box 286)
        - 1998 Dec. 12 (Box 286)
        - 1999 Mar. 12 (Box 286)
        - 1999 June 18 (Box 286)
        - 1999 Sept. 17 (Box 287)
        - 1999 Dec. 12 (Box 287)
        - 2000 Mar. 17 (Box 287)
        - 2000 June 16 (Box 287)
        - 2000 Sept. 9 (Box 287)
        - 2000 Dec. 8 (Box 287)
        - 2001 Mar. 23 (Box 287)
        - 2001 June 22 (Box 287)
        - 2001 Sept. 14 (Box 288)
        - 2001 Dec. 7 (Box 288)
        - 2002 Mar. 22 (Box 288)
        - 2002 June 21 (Box 288)
        - 2002 Sept. 14 (Box 288)
        - 2002 Dec. 6 (Box 288)
        - 2002 Dec. 13 (Box 288)
        - 2003 Mar. 7 (Box 288)
        - 2003 June 20 (Box 289)
        - 2003 Sept. 13 (Box 289)
        - 2003, Dec. 5 (2 folders) (Box 289)
        - 2004, Mar. 20 (Box 289)
        - 2004, June 11 (Box 289)
        - 2004 Sept. 4 (Box 289)
      - To-Do Lists, LC Meeting, 2002 June 21-2003 June 20 (Box 290)
      - Research file (Box 290)
      - Research Binder, 4 folders (Box 290)
      - Americans with Disabilities Act Case, 2004:
        - Amicus Brief 1999, June 18 (Box 290)
        - ADA Table of Statutes (Box 290)
        - Court documents and discovery, 1999 July 16 (2 folders) (Box 290)
        - Discovery materials, 2003 Mar. 24 (2 folders) (Box 290)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 290)
        - NCCLU Legal Memo, 1999 June 18 (Box 290)
        - Relevant case documents from G. Powell, 1999 Oct. 29 (Box 290)
        - Hearing on discovery motion, order, and brief due dates, 2003 Feb. 24 (Box 290)
        - Correspondence/memos (Box 291)
        - Discovery (Box 291)
        - Defendant/1999 (3 folders) (Box 291)
        - Judge Tilley's decision, 2004 Feb. 13 (Box 291)
        - Notice of Appeal to 4th Circuit, 2004 Mar. 8 (Box 291)
        - ADA, Title II, State Action (Box 291)
        - ADA, Title II, Brief in support of motion of Democratic Party for summary judgement, 2003 June 30 (Box 291)
        - Amicus brief, 2003 May 27 (Box 291)
        - Hearing on discovery motions, 2003 Feb. 24 (Box 291)
        - ADA Research and NCCLU Legal Memo, 1999 June 18 (Box 291)
        - Submissions to the court, 2003 May 12 (Box 291)
        - Court documents (Box 291)
        - Court order denying plaintiff's motion for extension of time, 2003 June 3 (Box 291)
        - ADA Title II, 2003 (Box 291)
        - Discovery, 2003 Feb. (3 folders) (Box 291)
  - Paralegal Office Subseries, 1987-2000, 60 boxes
    Office files regarding ACLU of NC legal cases, apparently housed separately from the Legal Program files and maintained by the ACLU of NC Legal Foundation's paralegal staff. Cases and subjects are likely to overlap with files in other series. As with other legal files, the names of the defendants and others have been redacted from this collection guide but are present on folder titles in the boxes.
    - School uniforms and religious rights, 1999-2000, folders 1-47 of 65 (Box 292-296)
    - School uniforms and religious rights, 1999-2000, folders 48-65 of 65 (Box 297)
    - UNC Library search, 1997 (Box 297)
    - Prison, 1997, folder 1 of 2 (Box 297)
    - Prison, paralegal materials, 1997, folder 2 of 2 (Box 298)
    - ADA, 1995-1998, 5 folders (Box 298)
    - Collateral estoppel, open meetings act, 1997, 3 folders (Box 298)
    - Double jeopardy (Box 298)
    - Streakers (Box 298)
    - Internet, 1997 (Box 298)
    - Gay adoption, 1997 (Box 298)
    - Warrantless search, 1996-1997, folders 1-9 of 16 (Box 298)
    - Warrantless search, 1996-1997, folders 10-16 of 16 (Box 299)
    - Abortion and parental consent, 1996-1997, 6 folders (Box 299)
    - Abortion and parental consent, 1983-1997 (NC State Supreme Court case) (Box 300-301.1, 302-305)
      Large group of case files includes handwritten notes, research (photocopies of reports of other abortion rights cases, other relevant cases and articles), and court papers including dockets. Includes abortion rights court case involving Takey Crist in Raleigh, whose papers are at the Rubenstein Library.
    - Juvenile first degree rape and first degree burglary, 1997, 28 folders (Box 306)
    - Squaw, offensive school mascot, 1998, 3 folders (Box 307)
    - Religious radio and car, 1997 (Box 307)
    - Ku Klux Klan and Asheville, 1998 (Box 307)
    - Connick-Pickering (1st Amendment?), 1997 (Box 307)
    - Prayer at school graduation, 1997 (Box 307)
    - Banned from writing library, 1998 (Box 307)
    - Yadkin Co. Establishment, 1997 (Box 307)
    - Gay custody, 1997-1999, folders 1-4 of 14 (Box 307)
    - Gay custody, 1997-1999, folders 5-14 of 14 (Box 308)
    - Wrongful arrest, 1996-1997, folders 1-2 of 15 (Box 308)
    - Wrongful arrest, 1996-1997, folders 3-15 of 15 (Box 309)
    - Unlawful investigation and detention, 1997-1999, folders 1-15 of 18 (Box 310)
    - Unlawful investigation and detention, 1997-1999, folders 16-18 of 18 (Box 311)
    - Election laws, 1997-1999, folders 1-6 of 7 (Box 311)
    - Election laws, 1997-1999, folder 7 of 7 (Box 312)
    - Obscenity, 12 folders (Box 312)
    - Due process, 1996-1998, folders 1-7 of 12 (Box 312)
    - Due process, 1997-1998, folders 8-12 of 12 (Box 313)
    - Archives, 1998-2001 (Box 313)
    - Enfield, NC: Police brutality, 1998 (Box 313)
    - Religious freedom, 1999, 3 folders (Box 313)
    - Sexual misconduct, 1998, 2 folders (Box 313)
    - Onslow Co., separation of church and state, 1998, 4 folders (Box 313)
    - Thompson notebook, 1998, folder 1 of 2 (Box 313)
    - Thompson notebook, 1998, folder 2 of 2 (Box 314)
    - PETA, first amendment, 1998 (Box 314)
    - Sovereign immunity, 1998 (Box 314)
    - Prior restraint, 1998 (Box 314)
    - Question over reasonable suspicion to conduct a search, 1996 (Box 314)
    - Unlawful search and seizure, 1995-1997, folders 1-11 of 12 (Box 314)
    - Unlawful search and seizure, 1995-1997, folder 12 of 12 (Box 315)
    - Correspondence, research, memos and notes, 1995, 11 folders (Box 315)
    - Police brutality, 1997 (Box 315)
    - Police brutality, 1998 (Box 316-318)
    - Police brutality, 1998, 5 folders (Box 319)
    - Double arrest, 3 folders (Box 319)
    - Anti-loitering ordinance, 7 folders (Box 319)
    - Good Shepherd Soup Kitchen, police holding ID cards, 2 folders (Box 319)
    - Illegal search and seizure, 1995, folder 1 of 9 (Box 319)
    - Illegal search and seizure, 1995, folders 2-9 of 9 (Box 320)
    - Religion and custody, 1991 (Box 320)
    - Custody 1996, 2 folders (Box 320)
    - Private property, 1996 (Box 320)
    - Anti-loitering law, 1993 (Box 320)
    - Anti-loitering law, 1993, 2 folders (Box 320)
    - Anti-loitering law, 1993, 4 folders (Box 321)
    - Imprisonment without trial, man with low IQ (Box 321)
    - Due process, 1997 (Box 321)
    - Traffic arrest, 1997 (Box 321)
    - No pants in jail, 1996 (Box 321)
    - Appeal of a ruling that a municipality is not a person and not subject to suit, 5 folders (Box 321)
    - No talking in the cafeteria rule at Woodhill Elementary school, 4 folders (Box 321)
    - Sheriff's deputy demoted for considering running against sheriff, 2 folders (Box 321)
    - Complaint for denied request, 4 folders (Box 321)
    - Prisoner rights, 8 folders (Box 321)
    - Illegal search and seizure, 1996, 8 folders (Box 322)
    - Right to a speedy trial, 1996, 2 folders (Box 322)
    - Right to a speedy trial 1996, 3 folders (Box 322)
    - Religious freedom, 1997, 3 folders (Box 323)
    - Equal opportunity funding of public schools, 1996, 17 folders (Box 323)
    - Employment and wages in NC, 1994 (Box 324)
    - Economic profile of NC and its counties, 1994 (Box 324)
    - Education and test files, 1993, 2 folders (Box 324)
    - Education files, 1997 (Box 324)
    - Rejects, 1992 Jan.-July, folder 1 of 2 (Box 324)
    - Rejects, January 1992-July 1992, folder 2 of 2 (Box 325)
    - Broughton Papers, 1992 (Box 325)
    - James City (Box 325)
    - Working conditions, 1992 (Box 325)
    - NCCU Search (Box 325)
    - Durham Housing Authority, 4th Amendment, 1991 (Box 325)
    - AIDS Home Chapel Hill, 1990 (Box 325)
    - Search warrant, 1993 (Box 325)
    - Abuse by police officer, 1993 (Box 325)
    - Prison rights, 1993 (Box 325)
    - Police misconduct, 1993 (Box 325)
    - Health insurance, 1993 (Box 325)
    - Electrical contractor discriminated against and slandered by County officials, 1992 (Box 325)
    - Search warrant, 1992 (Box 325)
    - Socialist Workers' Party, 1992 (Box 325)
    - Wilmington drug dogs in schools, 1987 (Box 325)
    - Durham schools cut programming for pregnant teenagers, 1991 (Box 325)
    - Domestic violence, 1991 (Box 325)
    - Medical negligence, 1991 (Box 325)
    - Prison censorship, 1990 (Box 325)
    - District Court conduct, 1993 (Box 325)
    - Tanning salon discrimination and HIV testing, 1993 (Box 326)
    - Abuse by mall security officers, 1993 (Box 326)
    - Wildlife officer harassment, 1993 (Box 326)
    - Search warrant, unlicensed police offender and criminal record, 1993 (Box 326)
    - Racial discrimination in schools, 1993 (Box 326)
    - Elementary school re-roofing project, 1992 (Box 326)
    - Search and seizure and HIV testing, 1992 (Box 326)
    - Triangle Swim Club racial discrimination, 1992 (Box 326)
    - Police conduct, 1990 (Box 326)
    - HIV testing, 1994-1996, folders 1-13 of 17 (Box 326)
    - HIV testing, 1994-1996, folders 14-17 of 17 (Box 327)
    - Drug tax law, 1996, 14 folders (Box 327)
    - Criminal record, 1997, 6 folders (Box 327)
    - Drug accusations by co-worker, 1996, folder 1 of 8 (Box 327)
    - Drug accusations by co-worker, 1996, folders 2-8 of 8 (Box 328)
    - Free speech, 1996, 5 folders (Box 328)
    - Criminal contempt and free speech, 1996, folders 1-6 of 10 (Box 328)
    - Criminal contempt and free speech, 1996, folders 7-10 of 10 (Box 329)
    - Criminal contempt and free speech continued, 1995, 7 folders (Box 329)
    - Industrial Commission and Tort Claims Act, 1996, folders 1-3 of 6 (Box 329)
    - Industrial Commission and Tort Claims Act, 1996, 4-6 of 6 (Box 330)
    - Strip search procedure, 1996, 3 folders (Box 330)
    - Determination to try juvenile as an adult, 1994, 4 folders (Box 330)
    - Determination to try juvenile as an adult, 1994, continued, folders 1-5 of 8 (Box 330)
    - Determination to try juvenile as an adult, 1994, continued records, folders 6-8 of 8 (Box 331)
    - Determination to try juvenile as an adult, 1994, continued records, folders 1-10 of 13 (Box 331)
    - Determination to try juvenile as an adult, 1994, continued records, folders 11-13 of 13 (Box 332)
    - ACLU Motions and Briefs at COA, 1994-1997 (Box 332)
    - Pembroke State University Student Activities Assistant Programming Director, living proximity to campus, 1993 (Box 332)
    - Right to trial by jury for rape charge, 1993, 5 folders (Box 332)
    - Petition for writ of habeas corpus following death sentence, 1992, 2 folders (Box 332)
    - Wearing a fez in prison, 2 folders (Box 333)
    - Police brutality, 10 folders (Box 333)
    - Insufficient counsel, 1 of 4 folders (Box 333)
    - Insufficient counsel, 2-4 of 4 folders (Box 334)
    - Mecklenberg County Jail: rape in jail, 1-7 of 8 folders (Box 334)
    - Mecklenberg County Jail: rape in jail, 8 of 8 folders (Box 335)
    - Statesville: Ku Klux Klan, 6 folders (Box 335)
    - Harnett County schools: race discrimination, 3 folders (Box 335)
    - Greene County: voting rights (Box 335)
    - Illegal search (Box 336)
    - NC Bar file (Box 336)
    - Contractor statute, discrimination, 2 folders (Box 336)
    - Reversal or remand of preliminary injunctions (Box 336)
    - Injunction (Box 336)
    - Issues, 2 folders (Box 336)
    - Raleigh Woman's Health v. NC: parental consent (Box 336)
    - NC House Bill 481 (Box 336)
    - Daily Tar Heel v. UNC: open meetings, 1998 (Box 337)
    - Judge orders use of birth control as condition for reunification with child. 1997, 8 folders (Box 337)
    - Disclosure of medical information, 1998 (Box 337)
    - Unlawful search and seizure, 1997, 5 folders (Box 337)
    - Daughter suspended for wearing Marilyn Manson t-shirt to school, 1998, 5 folders (Box 338)
    - First Amendment, 1996, 3 folders (Box 338)
    - Unreasonable search and seizure, 1998, 5 folders (Box 338)
    - Welfare reform, 8 folders (Box 339)
    - Family cap (Box 340)
    - Lobbying materials (Box 340)
    - Federal info (Box 340)
    - Potential clients (Box 340)
    - Senate bill 35 (Box 340)
    - Illegitimacy (Box 340)
    - House bill 5 (Box 340)
    - AFDC program (Box 340)
    - Privacy rights, 1998 (Box 340)
    - Religious exemption from building permit requirements, 1998, 2 folders (Box 340)
    - DWI, 1998 (Box 340)
    - Sons of Confederate Veterans: denial of special registration plates by DMV, 1998, 10 folders (Box 340)
    - Pre-employment polygraph test, FBI, 1998, 1-4 of 9 (Box 340)
    - Pre-employment polygraph test, FBI, 1998, 5-9 of 9 (Box 341)
    - Psychic ban, 5 folders (Box 341)
    - Unreasonable detention of student, 12 folders (Box 341)
    - Prayer at community college graduation (Box 341)
    - Student search (Box 341)
    - Police officer op-ed (Box 341)
    - Abortion clinic sued for performing abortion without parental consent, 11 folders (Box 341)
    - Planned Parenthood of the Triad info (Box 342)
    - Employees' rights of expression and association, 3 folders (Box 342)
    - Challenge of statute criminalizing protest activities at health clinics, 1-5 of 13 folders (Box 342)
    - Challenge of statute criminalizing protest activities at health clinics, 6-13 of 13 folders (Box 343)
    - In re Jane Doe: parental consent, 4 folders (Box 344)
    - Restrictions on funding of medically necessary abortions for indigent women, 13 folders (Box 344)
    - NC nursing board: investigation into termination of employment, 94 folders (Box 345)
    - Convicted drug dealer required to wearing clothing identifying him as a dope dealer by terms of probation, 3 folders (Box 345)
    - Strip search, 6 folders (Box 345)
    - Council of Churches: free speech, 1-4 of 19 folders (Box 345)
    - Council of Churches: free speech, 5-19 of 19 folders (Box 346)
    - Exclusion of black jurors, 5 folders (Box 346)
    - Exclusion of Jehovah's Witnesses from jury, 3 folders (Box 346)
    - Incident involving a woman with MS not able to find adequate access to a courtroom to attend the trial of her nephew, 9 folders (Box 347)
    - Cable access determination of adult material, 5 folders (Box 347)
    - Hair criminal contempt case (Box 348)
    - Union County middle school, same-sex classes (Box 348)
    - Wiccan banned from participation in school event (Box 348)
    - Chapel Hill disclosure campaign (diskette) (Box 348)
    - Tarot card arrest (Box 348)
    - Public school buses used to transport children to bible school (Box 348)
    - Political action committee, free speech, campaign finance, 1-2 of 14 folders (Box 348)
    - Political action committee, free-speech, campaign finance, 3-14 of 14 folders (Box 349)
    - First Amendment, 8 folders (Box 350)
    - Unreasonable search, DWB, 4 folders (Box 350)
    - Permit withheld from facility for treating AIDS patients (Box 350)
    - Conditions of Mecklenberg County intake center (Box 350)
    - Air time for a rap CD at WKNC (Box 350)
    - Malpractice insurance, 1995-1996 (Box 350)
    - Search without warrant (Box 350)
    - Utilities commission, restriction on calls (Box 350)
    - Employee wanted to go into business for himself, employer brings charges against him (Box 350)
    - Homeowner's association preventing the effective placement of television satellite dish, free speech claim (Box 350)
    - Prisoner rights (Box 350)
    - Warren County Noise Ordinance (Box 350)
    - Non-resident crab license (Box 350)
    - Wake County DSS policy concerning HIV patients (Box 350)
    - Citizen participation in Trenton/Jones County Facility Plan (Box 350)
    - Adoption prejudice, dismissed case (Box 350)
    - In-school suspension (Box 350)
    - Disclosure of medical records (Box 351)
    - HIV confidentiality (Box 351)
    - Discrimination in issuing of ABC permits (Box 351)
    - Wake Stone Corporation: mining permits (Box 351)
- Audiovisual Material Series, 1978-2004, 2 boxes
  Houses various audiovisual media documenting activities of the ACLU of NC and issues of concern. Items separated from specific context are marked with original box number. Other items were found loose in boxes.
  Conditions Governing Access note
  [Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials requires production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact Research Services before coming to use these materials.]
  - unspecified (Box 352)
  - Videocassette from box 160, Censorship of article on birth control in public school paper (Box 352)
  - Audiocassette from Box 160, "L. speaks to Randolph Cty. Board President," 1978 (Box 352)
  - Two VHS videocassettes from box 228, Rescheduling of cable access show (Box 352)
  - Two audiocassettes from box 248, In God We Trust, Davidson County (Box 352)
  - Photographs from box 265, Macon County nativity scene (Box 352)
  - One VHS and two audiocassettes from box 268, Buncombe, Haywood, and Rowan County entanglement (Box 352)